Eric Bartsch

774-271-2941 | bartschED@gmail.com | Arvada, CO

GitHub: https://github.com/rickyb0127

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bartsched

Personal Site: https://ericbartsch.com

About Me

I am a full stack developer who specializes in JavaScript and JavaScript frameworks. I enjoy helping to architect and bring exciting project ideas to life.

Some of my interests outside of coding include cooking, nutrition, golf, video games, psychology, and trying to learn Korean.

Work History

DMC Global

Full Stack Developer

August 2022 - April 2023

- Worked to port existing quoting tool built in vbscript into a modern web application using React as a frontend framework
- Due to a lack of SalesForce licenses, created a tool to clone production quotes into test environment in order to reproduce bugs and speed up testing

Technology used: React.js, SalesForce, jsForce, AirTable, Ionic Framework

Nekle

Software Systems Engineer II

January 2019 - August 2022

- Worked remotely with a small team to develop applications for stakeholders, using various technologies
- Participated in design and code reviews to ensure best practices were being followed and maintained open communication between the frontend and backend team
- Created admin portal using Amazon Cognito to allow for easy application customization for non-technical users
- Lead iOS developer responsible for building mobile application to interface with graphql and node backend
- Worked with client to build out a game designed around buying stocks of teams for major sports tournaments including the NFL, NCAA basketball tournament, NBA playoffs
- Helped architect and plan the design of member management and POS web application
- Created custom Angular directives for front-end features, such as ahead of appointment waiver system, membership credit dashboard and membership credit history

Technology used: Vue.js, Vuex, TypeScript, AWS Lambda, GraphQL, Vue Material Design, Sequelize, iOS storyboard, Swift, Apollo, MySQL, Angular.js, Bootstrap, Grails, CoffeeScript, Postgresql

Sous Chef | The University Club of Denver

March 2017 - January 2019

- In charge of banquet events including menu design, product ordering and overseeing a team to deliver event service
- Expedited and managed the line during a la carte dinner service

American Express

Software Engineer III

July 2015 - January 2017

- Helped architect and build an internal company site used to share and upload videos
- Responsible for front end design and implementation using React
- Worked on automated testing framework utilizing Selenium to test internal admin application

Technology used: JavaScript, React.js, Bootstrap, REST, Java, Selenium, Jenkins

Education and Certifications

gSchool at Galvanize

Boulder, CO

6 month accelerated full stack web development program Areas of study: HTML, CSS, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript

Johnson & Wales University

Providence, RI

BS Hospitality Management AS Restaurant Management